Privacy Policy
==============

Estes Express Lines Privacy Notice
----------------------------------

_Effective **December 31, 2019**_

Your privacy is important to us. We provide this notice so you will be aware of (1) the types of personal information we may collect when you use our website, (2) why we collect it, (3) how we use it, (4) how we protect it and (5) with whom we may share it. This notice also tells you how to contact us with any questions or concerns.

### Information You Provide

You provide us with personal information while using certain features of this website. For example, if you request information or create a My Estes account, we ask for your contact details to enable us to fulfill your request.

Contact details include directory information such as your name, company address, phone number, fax details, and email address. If you have created a My Estes account, the details also include your username and password. We do not collect Social Security numbers. 

If you use other services, we will collect the information required to provide that service. For example, if you create an online Bill of Lading (BOL), we will collect the contact and delivery information for the person or entity who will receive delivery. Estes may collect other information on the site such as that which enables us to offer brokerage services with another carrier.

Our site also collects information you supply about a specific shipment. This permits authorized users access to tracking information or shipping documentation for the shipment.

We also collect other information to improve our services. For example, we collect feedback you provide in user or third-party surveys. Similarly, we collect location information if you access our site using a mobile device. We also collect general location information based on your IP address.

Finally, we collect data that you furnish us, or our service providers, to provide you with information and invoices. We may collect data to enable you to communicate with, and make payments through, Electronic Data Interchange (EDI).

From time to time, we may change the website to offer additional products or services. If you decide to exploit these changes, you may choose to submit more information.

### Using the Information You Provide

As explained above, we collect the personal or business information you supply us through this website. **Note that you may choose not to provide us with all of the information we request**. That said, such a choice may prevent us from providing you the services or information you request. In other cases, it may prevent you from taking full advantage of our site’s features. The collected information is used for three main purposes.

First, we use it for business purposes. These functions involve the services you request. For example, this is used to create your My Estes account, generate quotes, process transactions, schedule pickups, track shipments, generate shipment/transaction-related documentation, view that documentation, handle shipment-related claims, and provide brokerage services for third parties to make shipments on your behalf. The data is also used to allow you to review billing information and open invoices.

In certain cases, you may make payments through Western Union. In those cases, your information will be submitted to, and processed by Western Union. **Western Union’s Privacy Policy will apply to such data. This Policy will not apply.** For additional information about Western Union data processing practices, contact Western Union.

We may also use the data to communicate with you about our service offerings, as well as those of our affiliates and subsidiaries. We use it to gather your feedback about our products, services, and programs.

Second, we may use the information for technical purposes. For example, we may provide you with customized content based on your site usage, preferences, and location, along with other information you provide us.

We may also use the data to analyze and improve our online offerings, including website features, advertising, marketing communications, and to enhance our marketing strategy. This includes developing and customizing online advertisements for our services and those of our subsidiaries and affiliates. These advertisements are served to you on our website, on websites of our affiliates or subsidiaries, and on websites of third parties who participate in certain advertising networks with us.

Similarly, we may use the collected data to protect against fraud, physical damage, financial losses, and unauthorized transactions. We may also use it to handle claims, other liabilities, and manage risk. For example, we can use it to identify unauthorized users or security issues.

Finally, we use the information for other permitted legal purposes. For instance, we use it to comply with applicable laws, industry standards, and our internal policies. We may also use it to enforce and verify compliance with these laws, standards, and policies.

Similarly we use the information from our careers pages to assess applicants, make hiring decisions, and assist in other personnel management functions.

Note that we may combine the information we collect about you with data from other sources.

### Cookies and Automatic Data Collection

We receive or collect some information automatically when you visit our site or engage with our online content. Certain third-party service providers such as Google Analytics may also collect this information for us. This information is collected using technology features such as:

_Cookies_. Cookies are files stored on the device you used to access our website. Cookies can store information that allows our website to recognize whether a particular device has been used to visit it in the past. They may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences or information you provide while visiting the sites. They may also be used to provide you information of interest to you, including relevant advertising.

In addition, we use this information to evaluate our web traffic, improve our website and services, enhance our communications, and understand the effectiveness of our ad or promotional campaigns. For more information on your choices about cookies, see the Your Choices section below.

_Web Beacons._ We use web beacons or pixels that monitor some types of use. These beacons may provide us with information such as the IP address of the computer or other device that accessed the site. We use this information to understand activity patterns on our site, to improve site features, and to customize our content presentation, including online advertising.

_Online Advertising_. We provide online advertisements on other parties’ websites. We may engage third-party providers, such as Google Analytics, to evaluate users response to our ads. Estes may develop content and advertising based on the analytics and user information cultivated from cookies. For more information on your choices about cookies, see the Your Choices section below.

_Referrer Headers_. We may record referrer headers when you follow links to our website. These may be sent to us automatically by your web browser. In these cases, we may receive information such as the URL of the referring website, or the search queries used to find our site. We use this information to understand our web traffic, improve our services, to increase search engine accessibility, and to monitor our advertising campaigns.

The types of information that are automatically collected through these tools include your user experience data. This encompasses the pages you view, links you click or hover over, and website selections you make. We record the features you use and the preferences you set.

We also record technical data such as your browser type, browser version, your browser’s HTTP referrer header, your IP address, and the operating system and device you are using to access the website.

### How We Share Your Information

We may share information with trusted parties. This is done for three reasons.

First, we may share with other parties for business or operational reasons. These include our subsidiaries and affiliates. They also include third-party service providers that help us host and operate the website; gather, save, analyze and use information you enter into online forms; accept payments for services you order through the website; analyze data on website usage; send mail or email to you for marketing or promotional purposes; conduct surveys; or arrange for exchange of information and payments for shipping and other business purposes between you and Estes through Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) services.

We also share with other carriers when you enter an online request for brokerage or time-critical services to help you place your shipment with another carrier. This is generally done if we cannot meet your needs in a particular situation.

Second, we may share for advertising purposes. We share information with advertising networks to serve interest-based advertisements to you (1) on our website, (2) on websites of our affiliates and subsidiaries and (3) certain third parties who participate in advertising networks with us.

If you prefer not to receive advertisements through advertising networks, please follow the instructions in the advertisements to opt out of receiving them.

Finally, we may share for legal reasons. For example, we share information when reasonably requested or required by law enforcement or government authorities. We also share where required to by law or in response to appropriate legal process. This includes instances in which sharing is necessary for an investigation into illegal activity, or to prevent physical harm or financial loss. Information will also be shared in the event of bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, or if we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets.

### Online Advertising and Tracking

You may receive advertisements from us and from our ad providers. These ads have been selected and tailored based on website activity, service usage, information provided, or other information we or our ad providers have obtained.

It is also possible that this advertising has been tailored to the interests that advertisers have inferred from your website browsing. This includes our websites, as well as other websites or applications which have a third-party advertising partner.

We also may engage with third-party advertising networks. We share aggregate, but not personally identifiable information with these third parties. However, ad networks may set their own cookies, beacons, and similar trackers on your device. They may otherwise collect or have access to information about you, including usage information, by tracking your online activities over time, across third-party websites, and across online services.

We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these third parties. These ad networks may use the information they collect for their own purposes. We and our network advertisers may target advertisements for our products and services and those of our affiliates and subsidiaries on our website and on other websites you visit.

### Web Analytics

You may opt out of the aggregation and analysis of data collected about you on our Site by our web analytics vendor by clicking [here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) and installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.

### Your Choices

We offer you certain choices about our information collection, usage, sharing, and communication with you. Exercise of these choices may require verification of your identity, such as through a password. This is done to verify your identity.

You may opt out of receiving certain communications such as surveys and emails. Do this by contacting us as explained in the Contact Us section of this Policy. You also have the following specific choices:

_Cookies_. Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. That said, rejecting cookies may affect your user experience. In particular, you may not be able to use certain site features. Moreover, disabling cookies may invalidate cookie-reliant options such as targeted advertising opt outs.

_Geographic location_. When you use our website on your mobile device, you may choose not to share your location by adjusting the device’s location services settings.

Estes will take reasonable steps to honor your choices. Even so, you should be aware that it is not always possible to delete all of your information. For example, we may store personal information in long-term archives. We may retain an identifier to honor your opt out choices. We will continue to send you service-related communications,

Finally, we may need to retain your information record keeping, analysis, or other reasons, to the extent permitted by law.

### California Residents

If you are a California resident, you may contact us to request information about circumstances in which we share certain personal information with third parties for their marketing purposes.

To request information, please contact us as shown in the Contact Us section of this Policy. Our website recognizes do-not-track signals sent by your browser. Certain website services may not work correctly if your browser sends a do-not-track signal. You may need to adjust your settings in order to use those services.

### **The California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents to request certain information, once a year, regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send us an email using the contact information provided below in the “Contact Us” section.

If you are a California resident, as of January 1, 2020, you have the following additional rights:

* You have the right to request information about the categories and specific pieces of personal information we have collected about you, as well as the categories of sources from which such information is collected, the purpose for collecting such information, and the categories of third parties with whom we share such information.
* You have the right to request information about our sale or disclosures for business purposes of your personal information to third parties.
* You have the right to opt-out of the sale of your personal information to third parties. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.
* You have the right to request the deletion of your personal information. Please note that notwithstanding your request, California law permits us to retain certain categories of personal information for numerous purposes, including to complete a transaction initiated by you, to perform a contract between you are us, and to comply with a legal obligation, such as a record retention requirements.
* You have the right to not be discriminated against for exercising any of these rights.

If you would like to exercise one or more of the above rights, please contact us by following the “Contact Us” options listed below. Please note that we will use the information we have collected about you to verify your identity prior to executing your request.

### Children’s Privacy

Estes does not sell or give out to third parties the personal information of customers if Estes has actual knowledge that the customer is less than 16 years of age, unless the consumer, in the case of customers are between 13 and 16 years of age, or the customer’s parent or guardian, in the case of customers who are less than 13 years of age, has affirmatively authorized the sale or given out to third parties of the customer’s personal information.

### Information Security

The nature of our business requires us to collect and maintain certain personal information. **It must be understood the Internet is not a secure medium. No program can guarantee data breach protection.** However, we understand the need to protect your personal information. To do so, we maintain appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards. These are designed to safeguard your personal information from accidental, unlawful, or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure, or use. Your My Estes account is protected by your log-in credentials. Please keep these secure and confidential.

We use the Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure (HTTPS) communications protocol.

Many services we provide on this website use access codes or passwords. These provide another layer of security for your information.

We communicate Estes’ privacy and security standards to our employees who access personal information. Access must be for business reasons. The information is physically located in a separate part of our facilities. Access to those premises requires a key card. We monitor employees, facilities, and systems periodically in an effort to prevent unauthorized access.

### Information Access and Correction

Estes seeks to maintain accurate information and provide you with options to update your information. You can log into your account and modify your information using your log-in credentials. You also may request that we update your information by contacting us as described in the Contact Us section of this Policy.

### Information for Users Outside the United States

This website is designed to comply with the laws of the United States of America. If you are a user located outside the United States, please be aware that information we collect will be transferred to and stored on our servers in the United States. By using our website, you agree to the transfer and processing of your personal data in the United States. United States data protection laws may differ from the laws in your country of residence.

### Links

We may provide links to other websites for your convenience and information. These sites are not owned, controlled, or operated by Estes. As a result, we cannot control how information collected by these linked sites will be used, shared, or secured.

If you visit linked sites, please review the privacy notices or policies posted at those sites. Estes has no control over the information practices of those sites.

### Contact Us

You may submit a question, correction, update, or complaint by contacting us at:

Email [TeamSocial@estes-express.com](mailto:TeamSocial@estes-express.com)

_Via USPS at:_

Webmaster  
c/o Corporate Strategic Services Dept.  
Estes Express Lines  
P.O. Box 25612  
Richmond, VA 23260-5612

### Updates

From time to time, we revise and update this Policy. The revisions reflect changes in practices, technology, or legal requirements. We change the effective date on the Policy to reflect when it was last revised.

##### Shipping

##### Support

##### Company

#### We're Here For You!

Copyright © 2024 Estes Express Lines, All Rights Reserved

##### Logout

×

Are you sure you wish to log out?

Confirm Cancel
